每天你都有机会跟别人擦身而过
You brush past so many people every day.
你也许对他一无所知
Some you may never know anything about,
不过也许有一天  他会变成一个朋友或者是知己
but others might become your friend someday.
我是一个警察  我的名字叫作何志武
I'm a cop. My name is He Qiwu,
编号223
and 223 is my badge number.
让开
Move it!
站住
Freeze!
别挡路
Out of the way!
我们最接近的时侯  我跟她之间的距离只有0.01公分
That was the closest we ever got just 0.01 cm between us.
57个小时之后
Fifty-seven hours later,
我爱上了这个女人
I fell in love with this woman.
喂  伯母  我是阿武
Hello? Ma'am? This is Qiwu.
我不是找阿May的
No, I called to talk to you, not May.
我是特地打电话来问候你的
你好吗?
How are you?
我?  没事没事
Oh, I'm fine.
她呢  是脾气大了一点  让她冷静一下
Yes, best to let May cool down for a while.
她想通了会打电话给我的
I'm sure she'll call when she's ready.
喂  伯母  你千万别跟她说我打过电话来  好不好?
Please don't tell her I called, okay?
噢  你要去看电影啊?  那我不打扰了
You're going to a movie? I won't keep you.
伯父呢?
Is your husband there?
喂  伯父  我是阿武
Sir? This is Qiwu.
不是  不是  我不是找阿May的  我是特地打电话来问候你的
No, don't call May. I just called to say hi to you.
你的咳嗽好了没有?
Is your cough better?
噢  你们赶时间啊?  那么我不打扰你们了  你们去啊  没关系
You're rushing out? I won't keep you then. No, it's all right.
噢  四姐在不在你这边啊?  不在啊?
Is May's sister there? No?
三姐呢?  我想问候她
How about her other sister? I just wanted to say hi.
每一个人都有一个习惯  我的习惯呢
We all have our habits. Mine is to wait here
就是来这边等阿May下班
for May to get off work.
阿May很喜欢来这边  因为那个老板说她很像山口百惠
The boss here says she looks like Yamaguchi Momoe. She likes that.
最近我跟她分手了
She and I just broke up.
因为她说我越来越不像三埔友和
She wished I were more like Tomokazu Miura myself.
368复机
Message for account 368?
密码  "爱你一万年"
Password is "Love You for 10,000 Years."
阿明找我?  阿May吧?
Call Ming? You mean May?
拼给我听啊
Spell it.
M-I-N-G?  M-A-Y吧?
M-I-N-G? It's not M-A-Y?
你有没有听错啊你?  没有?
Sure there's no mistake? You're sure?
你懂不懂英文?
Don't you know English?
喂?  阿明啊?  我知道我知道
Ming? I knew it!
是阿May叫你打给我的吗?
I guess May asked you to call.
噢  我没事  叫她不要担心  好不好?
I'm fine. Tell her not to worry, okay?
我会好好地照顾我自己的
I'll take good care of myself.
可是如果她这么想念我的话呢?  你叫她自己打给我嘛
But tell her she can call anytime she wants.
不用麻烦你  对不对?
No reason to bother you.
啊?  她没叫你打给我?
She didn't tell you to call me?
那你找我什么事?
Then why did you page me?
去跑步?  你失恋了?
You're jogging? Did you get dumped again?
没有?  那为什么去跑步呢?
No? Then why go jogging?
比赛?  你神经啊
A race? You've lost your mind!
跑步这么私人的事情  怎么可以随便跑给人家看?
Jogging is private. You don't jog for an audience.
就这样  拜拜
Forget it. Bye.
每个人都有失恋的时候
We all get our hearts broken sometime.
而每一次我失恋呢  我就会去跑步
Whenever I do, I go jogging.
因为跑步可以将你身体里面的水分蒸发掉
The body loses water when you jog,
而让我不那么容易流泪
so I don't cry as easily.
我怎么可以流泪呢?
I can't be crying.
在阿May的心里  我可是一个很酷的男人
May always thought I was a cool guy.
还没和好啊?
Still no go with your girlfriend?
都一个月了
It's been a month.
再找一个吧
Find someone else.
阿May吧  阿May不错的
How about May here? She's not bad.
你好
Hello.
她今天晚上早下班  你约她逛街吧
She's off early tonight. Ask her out.
她暗恋你很久了
She has a crush on you.
不行啊  今天约了人家
Can't. I have a date tonight.
改天吧
Some other time.
- 你们真的愿意做吗?  - 是的
- Are you sure you want to do it?  - Yes.
把护照给我
Give me your passports.
下一个
Next.
你  坐下
Hey, You! You! Sit down.
这个可以吗?
Is this one okay, miss?
- 一个大的  一个普通的  - 0K
- Get a bigger one, but nothing fancy. - OK.
喂  放下
Hey, Put it down!
别拍了  放下
I said don't shot, put it down.
别摸
Don't touch!
给大家啤酒
Give them some beers.
结帐
Check, please.
有时候我会在阿May家过夜
Sometimes I'd spend the night at May's.
可是为了不想让她爸爸妈妈知道呢
So her parents wouldn't find out,
每次我走的时候  我都会从阳台爬下去
I'd climb down from the balcony.
也不知道以后会不会有这个机会呢?
Will I ever get to do that again?
- 多少钱?  - 两千五百
- How much? - $2,500.
以后再说  好吗?
Latter, OK?
你在干嘛?  走
What are you doing? Go!
你们两个  过来
Hey, you two, come here.
跟着我  去结账
Follow me, go check it.
这个也是
These too.
过来
Come.
他不在这里
He's not here.
- 你知道他在哪里吗?  - 不知道  他说把这个交给你
- Do you konw where he is? - No. He left this for you.
罐头上面的日子告诉我
The date on the can tells me,
我剩的时间不多
I don't have much time left.
如果我找不到那班印度人  我就会有麻烦
If I don't find those Indians, I'll be in deep trouble.
为何穿雨衣?
Why the raincoat?
好像快要下雨了
I think it will rain.
不知道什么时候开始  我变成一个很小心的人
I don't know when I started being so cautious.
每次穿雨衣  我都会戴太阳眼镜
If I put on a raincoat, I wear sunglasses too.
你永远都不会知道什么时候会下雨  什么时候出太阳
You never know if it's going to rain or be sunny.
368复机
Messages for 368?
请问你密码?
Password, please.
"爱你一万年"
"Love You for 10,000 Years."
有没有人找我?
Anyone page me?
没有啊  整天没有人找你
No, no one's called for you all day.
谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
我们分手的那天是愚人节  所以我一直当她是开玩笑
We broke up on April Fool's Day, so I took it as a joke.
我愿意让她这个玩笑维持一个月
I'm willing to humor her for a month.
从分手的那一天开始
Every day I buy
我每天都买一罐5月1号到期的凤梨罐头
a can of pineapple with an expiration date of May 1,
因为凤梨是阿May最爱吃的东西
because May loves pineapple,
而5月1号是我的生日
and May 1 is my birthday.
我告诉我自己
I tell myself
当我买满30罐的时侯  她如果还不回来
that if May hasn't come back by the time I've bought 30 cans,
这一段感情就会过期
then our love will expire too.
先生  这个罐头明天就过期了
Sir, this can expires tomorrow.
那边还有很多  你再换一罐吧
Why don't you get another one?
没关系
It's all right.
明天早上最早一班班机是几点?
What time's your earliest flight tomorrow?
我要定位置
I want to reserve a seat.
一个人
One person.
- 你看过这几个人吗?  - 没有
- Have you seen these people? - No.
你要看清楚  也有孩子
Look carefully. They have kids with them.
我真的不知道
I really don't know.
- 你看过这些人吗?  - 没有
- Have you seen these people? - No.
- 这个人呢?  - 没有
- And this? - No.
没有吗?
No?
- 你真的不认识他吗?  - 不认识
- You really don't know him? - No, I don't.
我看见你跟他说过话
I've seen you talking to him!
- 爸爸  - 没事的
- Papa! - It's all right.
我的女儿呢?
Where's my daughter?
喂?
Hello?
你想怎么样?
What do you want?
给你一个小时  如果没有什么消息
If you don't have some news within an hour,
你永远不会看到你的女儿
you'll never see your daughter again.
喂  给她冰淇淋
An ice cream for her, please.
爸爸
Papa!
有的人为了钱  连子女都不要  但是他不像
Some men might sacrifice their own kid for money, but he wasn't one of them.
一个钟头之后  我就走了
One hour later, I left.
我是警察  站住
Police! Freeze!
我已经六个月都没有破过案
It's been six months since I nabbed anyone,
可是今天呢  终于抓到一个通缉犯
but I finally caught a wanted man today.
每一次我有好消息  我第一个想通知的就是我女朋友阿May
Whenever I had good news, I always wanted May to be the first to know.
喂?
Hello?
三埔友和  我要杀了你
I'll kill you, Tomokazu Miura!
啊  请问有没有5月1号到期的凤梨罐头?
You have any pineapple that expires on May 1?
- 今天几号了?  - 4月30啊
- What's the date today? - April 30.
是啊  明天过期的东西我们不会摆出来的
That's right. Think I stock outdated goods?
还有两个钟头  这么早就收掉了?
There's still two hours to go.
过期的东西没人要的  人家要买也要买新鲜的
Nobody wants stale goods. Get a fresh can.
新鲜新鲜  什么新鲜啊?  就是你这种人  喜新厌旧
With you people it's always "Out with the old, in with the new!"
喂  弄一罐凤梨罐头  要花多少新鲜  你知道吗?
You realize what goes into making a can of pineapple?
又要种  又要摘  又要切  你说不要就不要啊?
The fruit is grown, harvested, sliced -- and you just throw it away!
你有没有想过罐头的感受?
How do you think the pineapple feels?
先生  我只是职员  我负责卖东西的
Buddy, I just work here.
你叫我去想罐头的感受?
Who cares about the pineapple?
你有没有想过我的感受?
What about how I feel?
又要抬  又要搬  还要负责扔
I stock and restock this stuff all day.
我也希望那些罐头永远不会过期  我还省功夫呢
I wish it would never expire. It'd save me loads of work.
你那么爱过期罐头是吗?
You like expired canned food?
我这里有一箱  全送给你  不收你钱
Here you are. Take as much as you like. It's on the house.
不知道从什么时候开始
When did everything start
在每个东西上面都有一个日子
having an expiration date?
秋刀鱼会过期  肉酱也会过期
Swordfish expires. Meat sauce expires.
连保鲜纸都会过期
Even plastic wrap expires.
我开始怀疑  在这个世界上  还有什么东西是不会过期的?
I'm starting to wonder: Is there anything in this world that doesn't?
老师傅  秋刀鱼要不要?
Buddy, how about some swordfish?
过期的  不要  你要吧
It's expired. I don't want it.
不要?
You don't want it?
终于在一家便利商店  让我找到第30罐凤梨罐头
I finally found my 30th can of pineapples in a convenience store.
就在5月l号的早晨  我开始明白一件事情
As May 1 begins, I begin to understand.
在阿May的心中
In May's eyes,
我跟这个凤梨罐头没有什么分别
I'm no different from a can of pineapple.
不吃?  这么好的东西你都不吃
You don't want any? It's delicious.
有人说  狗是人类最好的朋友
People say dogs are man's best friend.
可是为什么在这个时候  它却不肯跟我分享我的痛苦呢?
So how come mine won't share my grief now?
不知道算不算是一个记录呢?
This must be some kind of record.
那一天晚上我吃掉所有的凤梨
I ate all 30 cans that night.
还好阿May不喜欢吃榴莲  要不然我一定是完蛋了
Good thing for me that May wasn't into durian.
我好想去庆祝一下
I feel like going out and celebrating.
阿May可能已经睡着了
May's probably in bed by now.
可是我不知道另外一个阿May呢?
But what about that other May?
哎  你回来干什么?
What brings you back here?
我今天心情好  想看子夜场
I'm thinking of going to a late movie.
嘿嘿  她走了  她走了
She's long gone.
走了?
Gone?
难道等你啊?  女人不能等的
You thought she'd wait around? Women can't afford to.
越等越会晚  越晚越担心
The longer they wait, the more nervous they get.
最后担心得像发疯一样
Drives them crazy.
刚刚跟路口那个Richard出去了
She just left with Richard.
你有意思的话早点儿来嘛
You gotta move quickly.
没想到在一夜之间
I never dreamed
我居然被两个叫阿May的女人抛弃
two Mays could dump me in one night.
为了要平复我的创伤
To get over it,
我决定不再找叫阿May的女人
I resolve never to go out with another May.
喂?  Lulu啊?
Hello? Lulu?
我是阿武啊
This is Qiwu.
出来喝杯酒吧?
Want to come out for a drink?
睡着了?
You're in bed already?
这么早啊?  这么早你能睡得着吗?
How can you sleep this early?
睡得着啊
You were asleep?
那没事了  拜拜
Never mind. Bye.
喂  千子惠吗?
Hello? Chieko san?
你猜我是谁?
Guess who I am?
对了  我是阿武啊
Bingo!
出来喝杯咖啡怎样?
Want to come out for a coffee?
什么?  你老公不答应  你什么时候结婚了?
Your husband won't let you? When did you get married?
五年多?
Five years ago?
怎么我们五年多没见了吗?
We haven't seen each other in over five years?
女儿都两个了
You have two kids?
你开心就好
You're happy. That's great.
祝你幸福
Well, all the best.
拜拜
Bye.
喂  请问江秀惠在不在?
Is Kong Siu-Wai there?
我是何志武
This is He Qiwu.
小学四年级同班同学  坐你隔壁的那一个啊
We went to fourth grade together.
你记不记得啊?
You remember?
哈哈  不记得啊?
You don't?
没事了  拜拜
Doesn't matter. Bye.
那30罐凤梨罐头吃得我的胃非常不舒服
Those 30 cans of pineapple had left me feeling queasy,
所以我去了一家酒吧
so I went to a bar.
因为听说酒可以帮助消化
I'd heard alcohol can settle the stomach.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
没事  没事  再给我一杯啊
Fine. Another double.
有一首歌叫作"日出时让恋爱终结"
There's a song called "Love Dies at Dawn."
我现在的心情就是这样
That's how I feel now.
怎么样才可以让我忘记阿May呢?
What can I do to forget May?
我跟我自己说
I tell myself,
从这一分钟开始  第一个进来的女人  我就会喜欢她
I'll fall in love with the first woman who walks in.
小姐  喝点什么?
What can I get you?
威士忌  谢谢
Whiskey, please.
我有一个预感  她一定会喜欢我
I have a feeling she'll like me,
可是为了保障我自己  我要问她一个问题
but just to be safe, I decide to ask her a question.
小姐  请问你喜不喜欢吃菠萝?
Excuse me, miss, do you like pineapple?
噢  她可能不是本地人
Maybe she's not Cantonese.
你喜欢菠萝吗?
Tell me, do you like pineapple?
Do you like Pineapple?
小姐  请问你喜不喜欢吃凤梨?
Do you like pineapple, miss?
国语讲得还不错嘛
Your Mandarin's not bad.
噢  我台湾来的嘛  你呢?
I grew up in Taiwan. What about you?
我现在不想说话
I'm not in the mood to talk.
请你走开
Please leave me alone.
你不用说话没关系啊
We don't have to talk.
我可以坐在这边吗?
Could I just sit here?
这里那么多位子  你干嘛一定要坐我旁边呢?
There are lots of seats. Why do you have to sit next to me?
因为我看你  你很寂寞啊
I can tell you're lonely.
是吗?
Really?
是
Yes.
一个女人  这么晚了还戴墨镜  只为了三个理由
There are only three reasons a woman would wear shades this late.
第一个呢  就说明她是个瞎子
First, she's blind.
第二个呢  就说明她在耍帅  所以要戴墨镜
Second, she's a poseur.
第三个呢  就因为她失恋
Or third, she got jilted
因为她不想让人家看出来她哭过
and doesn't want people to see she's been crying.
那你觉得我是属于哪一种呢?
And which one am I?
失恋
The jilted woman.
其实没关系嘛
It's okay.
失恋很平常啊  何必哭成这样子呢?
It happens all the time. Why cry about it?
失恋我也试过啊
I've been there too.
呐  我失恋的时候呢  我就去跑
I usually go jogging.
然后跑跑跑  跑到满身大汗的
I run until I work up a sweat.
这样子呢  我就没有泪可以流了
Then there's no water left for tears.
真的  你要不要试试看跑步?
Wanna try it?
我今天已经跑了一个晚上了  我很疲倦
I've been running around all night. I'm exhausted.
如果你想找人陪你聊天的话
If you're looking to chat,
请你找别人好吗?
please find someone else.
我不是想找人聊天的
I don't particularly want to talk.
我只是想陪你
I just want to keep you company.
因为我了解失恋的感觉
I know how it feels to have your heart broken.
一个女人失恋的时候  最需要就是一个肩膀
A heartbroken woman needs a shoulder to lean on.
你可以把我当成是你男朋友也没有关系啊
You can pretend I'm your boyfriend if you want.
我没有男朋友
I don't have a boyfriend.
我也没有女朋友啊
And I don't have a girlfriend.
你今年几岁?
How old are you?
我啊  我两个钟头之前呢  是24岁
Two hours ago, I was still 24.
可是我现在已经25岁了
Now I'm 25.
我是不会喜欢你的
I won't like you.
不要说得这么肯定嘛
Don't be so sure.
搞不好你再给我多一点时间  你就会喜欢我  对不对?
Give me a chance. We might hit it off.
你喜不喜欢吃凤梨嘛?
Do you like pineapple?
我喜不喜欢吃凤梨关你什么事?
What business is that of yours?
因为我想多了解你啊
I'm just trying to learn more about you.
我以前交一个女朋友  我们在一起5年
I was involved with a girl for five years.
可是之后呢  她跟我分手
But then she dumped me.
因为她说我根本就不了解她
She said I didn't understand her.
所以我想多多了解你啊
So I want to get to know you.
你是不会了解我的
You'll never get to know me.
你不让我了解你没有关系啊  可是你可以了解我啊  对不对?
Fine. Then try to get to know me.
你喜欢什么样的男人?
What kind of man do you like?
其实了解一个人并不代表什么
Actually, really knowing someone doesn't mean anything.
人是会变的
People change.
今天他喜欢凤梨
A person may like pineapple today
明天他可以喜欢别的
and something else tomorrow.
先生  先生
Sir!
打烊了
We're closing up.
They're closing.
要不要去跑步啊?
Wanna go jogging?
我  我想找个地方休息一下
I just want somewhere to rest.
我没有想到  她说的休息就是真正的休息
When she said "rest", I didn't think she actually meant it.
整个晚上  我看了两套粤语长片
That night, I watched two old movies on TV
吃了四次厨师沙拉
and had four chef's salads.
当天差不多快亮的时候  我知道我该走了
When the sun rose, I knew I had to go.
在我要走的时候  我帮她脱了鞋子
As I was leaving, I took off her shoes.
我记得我妈说过  如果女人穿高跟鞋睡觉
My mother used to say a woman's feet swell up
第二天脚会肿
if she sleeps in high heels.
她昨天晚上一定是走了很长的路
She must have walked a lot that night.
像她这样漂亮的女人  高跟鞋应该是要很干净的才对
Such a pretty woman should have clean shoes.
我是早上六点钟出生的
I was actually born at 6:00 a. m.,
还有两分钟我就25岁了
so I'll really be 25 two minutes from now.
换句话来讲
In other words,
我已经在这个世界上  经历了四分之一个世纪
I've spent a quarter of a century on this planet!
在这个历史性的时候  我去跑步了
To celebrate this historic moment, I go jogging.
我很成功地  让我身体里多余的水份蒸发掉
I'll get rid of my body's excess water.
我觉得很开心
It feels good.
要离开这个球场的时候  我留下了我的Call机
As I leave the track, I decide to ditch my pager.
因为我知道今天没有人再会Call我
I know very well no one's gonna call me today.
368复机
Account 368.
请说出密码
Password, please.
"爱你一万年"
"Love You for 10,000 Years."
你702号房间的朋友跟你说  "生日快乐"
Your friend in room 702 says happy birthday.
谢谢
Thank you.
在1994年的5月1号
On May 1, 1994,
有一个女人跟我讲了一声  "生日快乐"
a woman wishes me happy birthday.
因为这一句话  我会一直记住这个女人
Now I'll remember her all my life.
如果记忆也是一个罐头的话  我希望这罐罐头不会过期
If memories ever come in a can, I hope that can never expires.
如果一定要加一个日子的话  我希望它是一万年
If it has to have a shelf life, I hope it's 10,000 years.
给我一支烟
Give me a cigarette.
- 下雨了  - 是吗?
- It's raining. - Oh, yeah?
[期限: 1994年5月1日]
一杯可乐
A Coke, please.
哎  你又去跑步了?
Jogging again?
大男人一天到晚去跑步  这可不是办法
Running around isn't gonna solve anything.
阿菲呀  阿菲不错的
Listen, Faye's not bad either.
谁是阿菲啊?
Who's Faye?
啊  老朋友才告诉你  她今天才上班
Just started here today.
你要就快点  要不然又便宜Richard了
Make your move before Richard beats you to it.
- 可是我不喜欢男人  - 男人?
- I'm not into guys. - Guys?
让一让  让一让
Coming through!
我跟她最接近的时候  我们之间的距离只有0.01公分
That was the closest we ever got just 0.01 cm between us.
我对她一无所知
I knew nothing about her.
六个钟头之后
Six hours later,
她喜欢上了另外一个男人
she fell in love with another man.
一份厨师沙拉  谢谢
Chef's salad, please.
拿走还是在这儿吃的?
For here or to go?
拿走的
To go.
你新来的?  没见过你啊
You new here? I haven't seen you before.
你喜欢听这么吵的音乐啊?
You like listening to loud music?
对啊  吵一点挺好
Yes. The louder the better.
不用想那么多事啊
Keeps me from thinking so much.
你不喜欢想事情啊?
You don't like to think?
那你喜欢什么?
What do you like?
不知道  想起来再告诉你
I'll tell you when I find out.
你呢?
And what do you like?
厨师沙拉
Chef's salad.
老板  一份厨师沙拉
A chef's salad, boss.
又是厨师沙拉?
Chef's salad again?
每天晚上吃不烦啊
Aren't you tired of them yet?
- 买给别人吃的  - 女朋友啊?
- It's not for me. - Your girlfriend?
她爱吃厨师沙拉啊?
Is that her favorite?
买惯了嘛  她也没说她不爱吃
She never said it wasn't.
她是没说出来  你怎么知道她不想尝尝新东西呢?
Maybe she'd like something different for once.
炸鱼薯条  很好吃的
Try fish and chips. It's delicious.
万一她不喜欢吃怎么办?
What if she doesn't like it?
那么你就买一份厨师沙拉  再买一份炸鱼薯条
Get both and let her choose.
不就得了
You can't go wrong.
- 浪费钱  - 十几二十块嘛
- Isn't that wasting money? - It's not that much.
让她有个选择不好吗?
It's good to give her a choice.
好啊  一份厨师沙拉  一份炸鱼薯条
Okay. One chef's salad, one fish and chips.
好
All right!
谢谢
Thanks.
老板  一份炸鱼薯条
Fish and chips, please, boss.
对不对?
See?
我早说过她会爱吃  你不信?
I told you she'd like it.
就是嘛
You were right.
不爱吃厨师沙拉也不说
She never told me she didn't like chef's salad.
你又...
You never --
你又没有让她选择
You never gave her a choice.
有选择  她自然会说话啦
If you had, she might have told you.
反正换口味  今天晚上尝尝Pizza吧?
Anyway, now you broke the routine. Try pizza tonight.
Pizza?  不知道她喜不喜欢吃
I don't know if she'd like pizza.
还是那一招  一份炸鱼薯条  一份Pizza
Then do the same thing: Get both.
多花几十块嘛  别担心
It won't break the bank.
好吧
Okay.
怎么样?  今天晚上要不要尝点儿什么新的啊?
Want to try something different again?
热狗啊?  热狗不错啊
The hot dogs are good.
不用了  给我一杯咖啡
No, thanks. Just black coffee.
嗯?  你不买宵夜给女朋友吃了?
Nothing for your girlfriend?
她走了
She left.
为什么啊?
Why?
她说想换换口味
Said she wanted to try some new dishes.
也对
I guess she's right.
宵夜都那么多选择  何况男朋友
Plenty of choice in men, just like food.
好好的厨师沙拉嘛  换什么炸鱼薯条
I guess I should've stuck with the chef's salad.
小事情
It's no big deal.
她不换换口味  又怎么知道你是真材实料
She'll try someone else and see you're better.
早晚会回来找你的  你放心
She'll come running back. Don't worry.
谢谢
Thanks.
每一架飞机上面  一定有一位空中小姐是你想泡的
On every flight, there's one stewardess you long to seduce.
去年的这个时侯  我非常成功地
This time last year, at 25,000 feet,
在两万五千尺的高空上泡了一位
I actually seduced one.
我以为会跟她在一起很久
I thought we'd stay together for the long haul,
就像一架加满了油的飞机一样  可以飞得很远
flying like a jumbo jet on a full tank.
谁知道飞机中途转站
But there was an unexpected change of course.
给我一杯咖啡
Black coffee, please.
都一个星期了  她还没回来找你啊?
A week and she's not back?
让一下
Excuse me.
也许她在外面真的有很多选择吧
Maybe she does have lots of choices.
那你不要等了  她选择她的
Then put her out of your mind.
你也换换口味嘛
You have plenty of choices too.
每晚都喝咖啡  可不行啊
Black coffee every night's no good for you.
说换就换
Can't change just like that.
慢慢来好了
Have to go slow.
没事的  放心吧
Don't worry. I'll be okay.
没事最好
If you say so.
对不起  是不是有个警察每天晚上来这里买厨师沙拉?
Excuse me. The policeman who buys a chef's salad here every night ...
噢  你说663啊?
You mean No. 663?
他今天休假了
He's off today.
他不是星期六休假吗?
Isn't he off on Saturdays?
换班了  他没告诉你吗?
He changed shifts. Didn't he tell you?
如果你看到他的话  麻烦你帮我交给他好不好?
If you see him again, could you please give him this?
好的  没问题
Sure, no problem.
谢谢
Thank you.
[你的位置被取消]
[把钥匙还给你]
- 我有事出去一下  - 啊?
- I have to step out. - What?
- 我有事出去一下  - 噢
- I have some things to take care of. - OK.
- 我有事出去一下  - 啊?
- I have to step out. - What?
- 喂  你上哪儿去啊?  - 我也出去一下嘛
- Where are you going? - I have to go out too.
嗨  今天晚上就你一个人看店啊?
You here alone tonight?
怎么就你一个人看店啊?
刚才还都在这儿呢
Everyone was here a minute ago.
你来  他们就全部出去了
They ran off just as you walked up.
我哪里不对劲啊?
Something wrong with me?
没有啊
No.
- 咖啡  - 谢谢
Black coffee. - Thanks.
昨天晚上
Last night ...
有个女孩儿
some girl --
什么?
What?
昨天晚上有个女孩
Last night some girl --
你可不可以把收音机关小声一点啊?
Can you turn that music down a bit?
昨天晚上有个女孩  等了你很长时间
A girl waited around a long time for you last night.
留下一封信  说要交给你的
She left a letter for you.
是吗?
Really?
对啊  是个空姐
A stewardess.
- 呐  你看看?  - 喝完咖啡再说
- You wanna read it? - After my coffee.
喂  你还没拿信呢
Hey, your letter!
放着吧  改天来拿
Keep it for me. I'll get it next time.
喂  老板
Hey, boss.
怎么今天是你啊?
What are you doing here?
是我呀
I'm on duty.
- 663呢?  - 他请病假
- Where's No. 663? - He's on leave.
请病假?
On leave?
他说被大头钉扎伤了  要留在家里养伤
Said he got hurt by a pin. He's recuperating at home.
大头钉?  还有这种事?  真他妈逗
Hurt by a pin? What's he talking about?
她走了之后  家里很多东西都很伤心
Ever since she left, everything in the apartment is sad.
每天晚上  我都要安慰它们才能睡觉
I have to comfort them all before I go to sleep.
你知不知道你瘦了?
You've lost a lot of weight, you know.
以前你胖嘟嘟的
You were so chubby before.
你看你  现在都扁了
Now look at yourself. You're so skinny.
何苦来的呢?  要对自己有信心才行
Have more confidence in yourself.
我叫你不要哭嘛  你要哭到什么时候啊?
I told you to stop crying. How long are you going to cry?
做人要坚强一点嘛
You have to be strong.
你看看你  窝在这里像什么样子?
You're so limp and shapeless. Look at you.
唉  好好  我来帮你个忙
I'll help you.
是不是舒服多了?
There. Isn't that more comfy?
怎么不说话?
Why don't you say something?
别生她的气了
Don't be mad at her.
每个人都有不清醒的时候
We all have moments of doubt.
给她个机会
Give her a chance.
好不好?
Okay?
是不是很寂寞啊?
Feeling lonely?
才几天嘛  用得着这样
You're a real mess.
你冷啊?  我给你点温暖
You cold? I'll warm you up.
老板
Hello.
- 吃饭了没有啊?  - 吃过了
- How are you? - I'm fine.
东西在那边  要不要帮忙啊?
It's all ready. Need any help?
嗨  这点东西  不用了
It's not much. I'll manage.
让一下  让一下  对不起
Excuse me.
让一下  让一下  对不起  让一下  让一下
Pardon me.
- 哎  是你啊  - 喂
- Oh, it's you. - Hello.
你好了?
Are you better?
什么好了?
Better?
他不是说你被大头钉扎伤了啊
He said you got hurt by a pin.
听他瞎掰
Don't listen to his nonsense.
怎么最近老没见你啊?
You haven't been around much lately.
换早班了  现在巡这一区
I changed shifts. I'm on this beat now.
是嘛?
Really?
- 要不要我帮忙啊?  - 行啊
- Want some help? - Sure.
我走了
See you later.
哇  真够重的
It's so heavy!
这算轻的了
It's light today.
你的工作蛮辛苦的嘛
Your job must be hard.
打工就这么辛苦呗
Work's never fun.
为什么你会做这份工?
Why'd you take this job?
我表哥请不着人
My cousin couldn't find anyone else.
让我来帮忙  就暂时帮他了
I'm just helping out for now.
那你以前做什么?
What did you do before?
我做过的事可多了
Lots of things.
我存钱呢
I'm saving up.
读书啊?
To go to school?
没想过
Never thought of that.
我就是想玩
I just want to enjoy life.
打算去哪里玩?
How? Where?
随便呀
Anywhere.
加州
Maybe California.
加州?  加州好玩吗?
California? Is it fun there?
不知道  不好玩就到别的地方去
I said maybe. If it's not, I can move on.
你喜欢到处去玩啊?
You like to travel?
你不喜欢啊?
Don't you?
我无所谓  去也行  不去也行
I can take it or leave it.
那咱们约着一起去吧  我的钱就快存够了
You can come with me. I almost have enough.
改天再说吧
We'll see.
你这人怎么老这样啊?
Are you always like this?
那封信你到现在也没拿
You never came to get that letter.
我没空嘛
I've been busy.
这样吧  你把你的地址告诉我  我寄给你
Give me your address. I'll mail it.
免得丢了
Otherwise it'll get lost.
好啊
Okay.
就是这个地址?  咦?  你家挺近的啊?
You live close by.
是呀  就在前面有空上来坐啊
Yeah, right down there. Drop by sometime.
好呗  行啊  行啊
I will.
来  继续吧
Well, let's keep going.
哇  你出了那么多汗
You're really sweating.
你还行吗?
Sure you can manage?
行  没问题
I'm fine.
拜托  你不要老做白日梦了
Stop daydreaming, will you?
你以为你会唱两句就是歌星吗?
Think you're a rock star?
工作不做  老是拿着红萝卜当麦克风
You've been fooling around with that all day.
这是人家要来吃的
Who'd wanna eat it now?
要拿  拿卷卫生纸去
Use a toilet roll or something.
你呀你呀
You too!
我  我没做梦啊
I'm not daydreaming.
对对  你没做梦  你这是在梦游
That's right. You're sleepwalking!
对  梦游  梦游呗
That's right. I'm sleepwalking.
那就梦游吧
Whatever you say.
游吧
I'm sleepwalking.
那天下午我做了个梦
I had a dream that afternoon.
我好像是上他家去了
It seemed I was in his apartment
离开的时候  我以为我会醒过来
and that I'd wake up when I left.
谁知道  有的梦是怎么样都不会醒的
I didn't know you never wake up from some dreams.
有时候  我会回家吃饭
Some days I go home for lunch,
因为每一次回来我都可以有一个希望
because there's always a chance ...
我知道你回来了
I know you're in there.
你快点出来啊
Come on out.
我数三下
I'll count to three.
一
One ...
二
two ...
三
three!
她以前很喜欢从衣柜里跳出来吓我
She used to jump out and scare me,
可是最近少多了
but she hasn't done it much recently.
哼  说的也是  玩得多也会厌啊
I guess games get old after a while.
那她会不会藏在厕所呢?
Maybe she's hiding in the bathroom.
喂
Hello.
Hello!
傻瓜
Dummy.
- 你的叉烧饭  - 谢谢
- Roast pork and rice. - Thanks.
让一下  让一下  让...
Excuse me.
嗨
Hi.
- 又在这吃饭啊?  - 是啊
- Eating here again, huh? - Yes.
你还没吃完了吗?
Will you be here a while?
什么事啊?
Why?
啊?  没事  没什么
No reason.
你去哪里呀?
Where are you going?
我忘了拿点东西  得回去拿一下
I forgot something.
喂  对了  你那封信我还没寄呢
Oh, I still haven't mailed your letter.
没关系  有空再寄吧
No hurry.
没关系啊?  那等我有空再说吧
All right. I'll get around to it.
你怎么又搬回来了?
Why are you back?
我得赶交电费  先放这一会儿
I have to pay the electricity bill. Can I leave this here?
喂  表哥啊?
Hello? Cousin?
我现在还在菜市场了
I'm still at the market.
对啊  我这下大雨
It's pouring rain here.
特大  你听听
It's pouring. Listen.
真的假的?  我们这里出大太阳呢
What are you talking about? It's sunny over here.
地区性雷阵雨吧
Really? Must be a local shower.
行了  雨停了  我就马上回来了
I'll be back when it stops.
记住把电费交了
Don't forget the electricity bill.
知道了  知道了
I won't.
我走了
I'm going now.
行了  行了  知道了
It's okay.
我再来看你们  拜拜
I'll be back to see you soon.
拜
Bye.
请你吃的
These are for you.
干嘛买那么多荔枝啊?
Why all the lychees?
我串门去
They're for a friend.
你跑哪儿去了?
Where are you?
我不是交电费嘛
Paying the electricity bill.
要交这么久啊?
All this time?
对呀  人特多  挤都挤不过去
It's packed here. I can hardly get in the store.
我看且得交呢
I have to wait in line.
怎么可能每天都那么多人呐?  你交了好几天了
How come it's always so crowded? You've been trying for days.
我也没办法啊
I don't want to.
尽量吧  今天交不了  明天再来呗
I'm doing my best. Should I try again tomorrow?
不要了  这家人太多  你换别的地方去
Try another store.
换别的地方去?
Another store?
那我换了啊  我真的换了啊
Okay. You're sure?
你好
Hello.
嗨  你去逛公司啊?
Been shopping?
没有  我在帮一个朋友装修嘛
A friend is redecorating his place.
- 你很忙啊  - 对啊  我事特多
- You sure are busy. - I certainly am.
还喝咖啡呢?  别喝那么多  伤身体
Black coffee again. It's bad for you.
晚上睡不着多喝点水
If you can't sleep at night, drink water.
梦中人
Man in my dreams
一分钟抱紧
I hold you tight for a minute
接十分钟的吻
And kiss you for hours
陌生人
Stranger
怎样走进内心
You stole into my heart
制造这次兴奋
And set it all awhirl
我仿似跟你热恋过
I've been in love with you before
和你未似现在这样近
But never felt so close to you as now
思想开始过份
My thoughts careen out of control
为何突然袭击我
Why have you taken me by storm
来进入我闷透梦窝
Bursting into my dreary dreams
激起一股震撼
Sending shock waves in every direction
梦中人
Man in my dreams
多么想变真
I want you to be real
我在心里不禁
My heart can no longer resist
梦中嫱
Searching in my dreams
这分钟我在等
At this minute I'm waiting
你万分钟的吻
To kiss you for hours
喂  是我啊
Hi, it's me.
班机回香港了  要不要把位子留给你啊?
The plane's back in Hong Kong. Want to make a reservation?
我还是以前的那个电话  打给我吧  拜拜
I'm at the same number. Call me. Bye-bye.
哇  你的头发多漂亮啊  留了一些日子了吧?
Nice hair! Did it take long to grow?
关你什么事啊  神经病
None of your business.
够骚的啊?
Kind of a flirt, isn't she?
是啊
I guess so.
怎么了?
What is it?
没什么  不  你跟她挺熟的?
Have you known her long?
不是啊
No.
有一天  我突然心血来潮  我有一个感觉  她好像回来了
One day I had this sudden feeling she was back.
不知道是我忘了关水龙头
Did I leave the faucet running,
还是房子越来越有感情?
or is the apartment getting more weepy?
我一直以为它是最坚强的
I thought it would cope all right.
没想到它会哭得最厉害
I didn't expect it to weep this much.
一个人哭  你只需要给他一包纸巾
When people cry, you just give them a tissue.
可是一间房子哭  你可要多做很多功夫
But when an apartment cries, it's a lot of work to mop it up.
你怎么会在这儿啊?
What are you doing here?
- 这里是我的家  我当然在这里  - 你的家?
- I live here. - You live here?
你来这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
我没事  我买金鱼呗
I came to buy goldfish.
- 这里有金鱼卖吗?  - 没有啊
- Someone around here sell goldfish? - No.
- 那你说你来买金鱼?  - 对啊
Then why come to buy goldfish? - Yes.
你到底是买金鱼还是卖金鱼的?
You buying or selling?
什么呀?  你说什么呢?  我就是买金鱼呗
What? No -- I mean, I'm buying.
你问什么呀  我不知道  你别吓唬我
Stop it! I forget everything when I'm scared.
你怕什么?
Why are you scared?
我怕你呗  我看见你就害怕
I got scared when I saw you here.
那我走了
I'm going now.
你说要走  还站在这儿  还不走?
You said you were going. Well?
我动不了  我这腿能动我不早走了吗?
I can't move my legs. I'd go if I could.
你是不是抽筋了?
You have a cramp?
我不知道  我没抽过筋
I don't know. It's never happened before.
你还是进来坐一会儿吧  来啊
Maybe you should come in and sit down.
每一次她回来  我都会为她按摩小腿
When she'd return from a long flight, I'd massage her legs.
因为做空姐真的很辛苦
Being a stewardess is a tough job.
女人的小腿是最性感的
I've always found women's legs sexy.
自从她走了之后  我很久没有接触过了
But I haven't touched any since she left.
- 好一点没有?  - 好一点儿了
- Better? - I guess.
- 我能走了吧?  - 再坐一会儿
- Can I go now? - Stay a while longer.
给你听首歌
I'll put on some music.
你喜欢这首歌啊?
You like this song too?
我无所谓  我女朋友喜欢它
Not really. My girlfriend liked it.
你肯定你女朋友喜欢这首歌?
She really liked this song?
是呀
Yes.
我知道他女朋友喜欢的不是这首歌
I know it isn't true.
因为这张唱片是我前几天梦游的时候留在这儿的
That's my CD. I left it here a few days ago.
我开始怀疑梦游是否会传染?
I'm starting to wonder: Can sleepwalking be contagious?
可能因为刚才太紧张了吧
I guess I've been too nervous.
坐一坐就睡着了
After a while, I fell asleep.
那天下午  那个女孩子在我家里睡着了
The girl fell asleep in my place that afternoon.
本来我想叫她起床
I thought about waking her up,
不知道为什么我没有这么做
but for some reason I didn't.
糟了  糟了
Oh, no!
当心着火  小心啊
Watch out for the flames.
小心那些蜡烛啊
Make sure those candles are secure.
我真不明白你最近做什么?
What's gotten into you lately?
电费也不交  好了吧  现在电也被人剪了
Why didn't you pay the electricity bill?
你每天下午都去哪儿了?
Where have you been going every day?
我看病去了
I went to see the doctor.
看医生?  我怎么没见你吃药啊?
The doctor? I haven't seen you taking any medicine.
我吃了啊  你没看见嘛
You just didn't notice.
是  我没注意  那么医生说你什么时候会好呀?
Did he say when you'd get better?
快了  就快好了
Should be any day now.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
神经病
You're crazy!
不知道是不是因为换季
Maybe it's the change of season,
我觉得自己变了很多
but lately I've changed a lot.
我的观察力强了
I've become more observant.
开始注意一些我平常不会注意的事情
I notice things I used to take for granted.
怎么番茄青鱼有生鱼的味道?
Even the sardines taste different.
你不要自暴自弃嘛
You mustn't let yourself go.
前阵子看你还好好的  怎么一下子胖这么多啊?
You were fine before. Now you've suddenly put on weight.
她虽然不在  你还得见人啊
She left, but you have to carry on.
不要再放纵自己了  减肥
You can't go on indulging yourself.
我早就想骂你了
You know, I have to tell you:
你变了  你知不知道?
You've totally changed.
做人要有性格嘛
You can't just change personality like this.
就算她真的不回来  你也不要改变你自己啊
Her walking out is no excuse.
好好反省反省
I want you to think about that.
看着它哭的时候  我很开心
It was a relief when I saw it crying.
因为它外表好像改变了
It may look different on the outside,
可是它的本质没有变
but it's still true to itself.
它依然是条感情丰富的毛巾
It's still a very emotional towel.
觉不觉得我开朗了?
Have you noticed I've perked up?
我突然觉得什么东西都好看多了
Things are starting to look better.
以前我觉得你很笨
You used to look sorta dumb,
现在看起来蛮可爱的
but now you're looking quite cute.
别把自己弄得那么脏嘛
But you mustn't let yourself get so dirty.
以前白白的多好啊
You used to be so clean and white.
现在弄得黄黄的
Now you've turned all yellow.
你看你  还弄那么多疤
Look at these scars.
跟别人打架了?  啊?
Have you been getting in fights?
你怎么躲在这里啊?
Why were you hiding in there?
知不知道我找你多久了?
I've been looking all over for you.
你躲起来没有用啊
What's the point of hiding?
要面对现实才行
You have to face reality.
哇噻  发霉了
You're all moldy.
明天吧
Tell you what. I'm not busy tomorrow.
明天我有空带你晒太阳
I'll take you out for some sun.
你怎么会在我家里啊?
What are you doing in my apartment?
不是你叫我有空到你家来坐的吗?
You said to drop by!
快开门啊  不然我撞门了啊
Open up or I'll break the door down!
喂  有人找你啊
There's someone looking for you.
- 找我?  - 是啊
- Me? - Yeah.
- 你怎么会在这儿?  - 我来拿封信
- What do you want? - I've come for my letter.
什么信啊?  你问老板啊
What letter? Ask the boss.
问我干嘛?  在你那儿嘛
You were keeping it.
老板说在你那儿
He said you had it.
在我这儿?
I do?
在我这儿吗?
I have it?
对了
Oh, right.
我怕丢了  我帮你收起来了  我没有看过啊
I was afraid someone might take it. I didn't read it.
谢谢你啊
Thanks.
明天晚上有没有空?
Are you free tomorrow night?
干嘛问我明天晚上有没有空?
Why do you ask?
- 想约你出去  - 干嘛约我出去?
- I want to ask you out. - On a date?
老板说你明天晚上不用上班
The boss says you're off tomorrow.
不上班就得跟你出去啊?
So I have to go on a date?
你考虑一下
Think it over.
明天晚上八点  在对面那家"加州"等你
I'll meet you across the street at the California at 8:00.
这首歌不适合你听
That music's not your style.
听这首
Listen to this.
完了  完了
Damn it!
完了  完了  完了
Damn it, damn it, damn it!
喂  663泡妞真有一套啊
No. 663 is a smooth operator.
- 老板  你要学学663  - 神经病
- It's 663. - Whatever it is!
稍等
Wait!
- 加酱汁吗?  - 好的
- Chilli sauce? - Okay.
- 我的可乐呢?  - 可乐  没有杯子啊
- Where's my Coke? - I'm out of cups!
那天下午我在家里大扫除
I gave my place a thorough cleaning that afternoon.
我好像在清理跑道  准备第二架飞机降落
It was like clearing the runway for another plane to land.
那天晚上我早就到了"加州"
I got to the California really early that night.
因为我不知道飞机会不会Delay
I half expected a flight delay,
我换了十块钱零钱
so I got some loose change.
喂  麻烦你帮我换零钱
Change, please.
半个钟头后  我又换了十块钱零钱
Half an hour later, I broke another $10 bill.
我开始有预感那班飞机已经Cancel了
I started thinking maybe the flight was canceled.
她不会来了
She isn't coming.
她叫我把这封信交给你
She asked me to give you this.
用不着那么失望
Don't look so down.
泡不上她  可以泡别人嘛  对不对?
She didn't work out, so try another girl.
阿May明天又回来做了  泡阿May吧
May's coming back tomorrow. Give her a try.
- 她人呢?  - 她辞职了
- Where is she? - She quit.
她说去什么  加州什么的
Said she was going to California.
我走了
That's all.
谢谢
Thanks.
我没看那封信
I didn't read the letter.
因为有些事情需要时间去接受
Some things take time to sink in.
老板走了之后
After the snack-bar manager left,
我开始跟啤酒瓶讲话
I started talking to the beer bottles.
你失望了?
Disappointed?
不会啊
Not really.
回家睡觉吧  她不会来了
Go home to bed. She's not coming.
其实她不是没有来
Actually, she wasn't a no-show that night.
只是走错了地方
She just got the place wrong.
那天晚上我们大家都在加州
We were in different Californias
只不过我们之间相差了15个钟头
15 hours apart.
现在是她那边早上11点
It must be 11:00 a. m. over there now.
不知道今天晚上8点  她会不会记得约了我呢
I wonder if she'll remember our 8:00 p. m. date here.
嗨
Hi.
这么巧啊
What a coincidence!
不用值班啊?
Not on duty tonight?
放假
That's right.
你好吗?
How are you?
还不错  你呢?
Fine. And you?
很好啊
I'm okay.
一个人?
You alone?
不是  跟朋友
No, I'm with a friend.
很配啊
He's your type.
你还有东西在我家里
You still have stuff at my place.
有空上来拿吧
Come get it sometime.
我不要了  帮我丢掉了吧
That's all right. Just throw it out.
好
All right.
我要走了
I gotta go.
我还是比较想看你穿制服
I still think you look better in uniform.
你也是
So do you.
- 拜  - 拜
- Bye. - Bye.
哎  你买了东西  还没给钱呐
Hey, you didn't pay.
你帮我给吧
You pay for me.
- 多少钱?  谢谢  - 262元
- How much is it? - $262
谢谢
Thanks.
那天晚上我收到一张登机证  时间是一年以后
The letter turned out to be a boarding pass dated for one year later,
至于地点我一直没有看清楚
but I couldn't make out the destination.
[经济位  663先生]
其实那天我去了
I actually did show up that evening.
我知道八点的时候人多  我七点一刻就到了
I knew it would get crowded, so I got there at 7:15.
那天的雨特大
It was pouring outside.
看着窗户外边  我看见了下雨的加州
Watching through the window, I saw a rainy California.
我特想知道  另外一个加州是否阳光明媚?
I needed to know if the other California was warm and sunny.
所以我给了自己一年的时间
I decided to give myself one year.
今天和那天一样那么大雨
Tonight it's raining as hard as it was then.
望着窗户外边儿
Looking out this window,
我只是想着一个人
there's just one person in my thoughts.
不知道他到底打开那封信没有?
I wonder if he ever opened my letter.
你怎么会在这儿啊?
What are you doing here?
喂  你怎么会在这儿?
Hey! What are you doing here?
怎么是你啊?
Is that really you?
你干嘛?
Yeah. What are you doing here?
装修啊
Renovating.
装修?
Renovating?
我表哥呢?
Where's my cousin?
你表哥开卡拉OK了
He opened a karaoke bar.
他说想换换口味
Said he needed a change.
所以让给我了  他没告诉你吗?
He let me take over here. Didn't he tell you?
没有啊  好久没见他了
No, I haven't seen him.
你表哥真会做生意
He's a shrewd businessman.
刚开始介绍我买炸鱼薯条
First he sells me fish and chips,
现在连店都让给我了
and then the whole shop.
什么?
What?
我说  你表哥很会做生意
I said your cousin is a shrewd businessman!
你什么时候喜欢听这么闹的音乐呀?
Since when do you like this loud music?
花点时间  适应一下就行了
With a little time, I get used to things.
- 你不是去加州了吗?  好不好玩?  - 啊?
- Did you go to California? Was it fun? - What?
你不是去加州了吗?  好不好玩?
Did you go to California? Was it fun?
加州
California ...
就那么回事  没什么特别的
was okay. Nothing special.
你穿制服很好看
You look good in uniform.
你这身也不赖啊
You look nice like that too.
吃不吃东西?
Want something to eat?
不吃了
I better not.
明儿一早我还得飞呢
I fly out real early tomorrow.
什么时候回来?
When will you be back?
这里过两天就开幕了
My grand opening is in two days.
不知道
I don't know.
我这次可能得飞挺久的
This might be a long trip.
到了外国写封信回来嘛?
Write to me when you reach wherever it is.
写了你也不会看啊
You probably wouldn't read it anyway.
哎  有个事想问你
I have to ask you something.
如果有人给你这样的登机证
Would you let someone board
你会不会让他上飞机?
with a boarding pass like this?
日子是今天  可惜弄湿了
It's dated today, but it got blurred in the rain.
又不知道去哪儿的  你知不知道?
where it's taking me. Do you know?
不知道
No ...
要不然给你换一张吧
but I'll give you another one.
好啊
Great.
你想上哪儿啊?
Where do you want to go?
随便啊  你说去哪儿就去哪儿
Doesn't matter. Wherever you want to take me.
Written and Directed by
WONG KAR-WAI
Starring
BRIGITTE LIN
TONY LEUNG
FAYE WONG
TAKESHI KANESHIRO